♪♪
You're doing very well.
A little bruising and
swelling are perfectly normal.
Just continue taking it easy,
and I'll see you in
about two weeks, okay?
Thank you.
I just want to die every
time I look in the mirror!
How could he have
done this to me?!
You'll feel better after
you talk to Dr. Weston.
Please sit down.
The doctor will be right in.
Hello, Dr. Carr.
All set?
I'm ready if you are.
Take a seat.
Okay, I want you
to keep perfectly still.
I think you're gonna
be very pleased.
I want to see if I can
make the swelling
under your chin
go down a bit faster.
A couple of things I need.
I'll be right back.
Hey, Doc.
You're a genius.
Thank you.
Just look at me!
Look at my face!
Miss Ferguson, what you see
now is not what you're
going to see in six weeks,
- I assure you.
- I wanted a nose
like Elizabeth
Taylor's, now look.
I am gonna hit you
with a malpractice suit,
the likes of which
you have never seen!
Miss Ferguson, please,
you're overreacting!
Oh, what's the use?
She's an emotional wreck.
You should never
have operated on her.
Maybe the way I screen
my patients leaves something
to be desired...
but it seems to me you
have the same problem.
I do?
We need to talk,
Lowell... tonight.
That's all there is to it!
I don't care what kind of
position this puts you in!
You can't do this to me, Scott!
Yes, I can. I'll be damned
if I'm gonna let your
practice ruin mine!
It's not gonna happen!
Just as soon as I
talk to my attorney,
this partnership is
going to be terminated!
Good morning, Miss Ferguson.
My name is Dr. Lowell Carr.
I'm, uh, Dr. Weston's partner
- at the plastic surgery clinic.
- Yes?
I understand you're unhappy
with the rhinoplasty
that he performed.
I wondered if I might
have the opportunity
to talk to you about it.
You're not going
to change my mind.
I assure you.
This'll only take a moment.
Your paper.
Ooh, that coffee
smells wonderful.
Would-would there be another
cup where that came from?
Of course.
Have a seat.
Cream or sugar?
Black's fine. Thanks.
Thank you.
All right.
I'd like to propose that before
you take any legal action,
you and I get together
and see if we can find
a more constructive way
to rectify the situation.
What do you mean?
Well, for instance, I
could reconstruct the nose.
And if there's a problem
with some other
anatomical feature,
I could... I could
fix that, too.
Are you saying
that if I dropped
the malpractice suit,
you'll give me a free
tummy tuck or something?
My goal is to see you satisfied.
I don't want to keep you,
but why don't
you think about it,
and I'll... I'll give you
a call this evening.
I should be home around 7:30.
No, I-I have a dinner tonight.
Why don't you call
the office tomorrow,
and I'll tell Lori to
squeeze you in this week.
Okay.
Thanks for the coffee.
And thanks for coming by.
♪♪
Dr. Lowell Carr.
Okay.
Oh, thank you.
Lowell.
I just saw your piece
on your new skin grafting
procedure in the Journal.
It was terrific.
Well, thank you.
I'd like to see your
notes on the procedure.
Well, I'll send them
over first thing tomorrow...
If you agree that
we stop talking shop,
and you buy me a drink.
Deal.
♪♪
Miss Ferguson?
It's me, Dr. Weston.
♪♪
Yes, that's my knife,
but I don't know how it
ended up in Dr. Weston's back,
or how he ended up in
my house, for that matter.
We found this in his pocket.
It seems someone named
Doreen Ferguson called him
at 4:30 this afternoon,
told him to come to this
address at 7:15 tonight.
I didn't leave a
message like that.
But you are one of his patients.
Was.
I was, yes.
I went to him for a nose job.
I wanted him to
make my nose smaller
and make it go
up instead of down,
but thanks to that charlatan,
I went from having a beak
to having a snout!
Oh, my God.
You think I killed him.
Well, for the sake of argument,
where were you
around 7:15 tonight?
I was...
closing up the antique store I
work at down on Ballard Street.
- Anybody see you?
- You bet someone saw me.
The cretin who rear-ended me
when I pulled out
of the parking lot.
In fact...
here... here is his name.
Here is his phone number.
Here is his insurance company.
Oh, oh, and...
here is the badge number
of the police officer
who stopped to make
sure everything was okay.
Any other questions?
Nope.
- Doreen?
- Ellie.
That's my next-door neighbor.
Jim.
Okay.
Are you all right?
What happened?
That's Dr. Weston.
Someone murdered him in my
home to make it look like I did it.
Oh, my God, Doreen!
Miss?
Do you remember seeing
or hearing anything unusual
around 7:00, 7:30?
Um, uh, oh, yes, actually.
I-I saw a man go through
the door right about that time.
Can you describe him?
Um... he was the same man
that was here this morning,
you know, right before
you went to work.
We keep an eye on each other.
You know, attractive
single women living alone
cannot be too careful.
Who would that have
been, Miss Ferguson?
Dr. Carr.
I was at her house
yesterday morning, yes,
but not last night, no.
But were you at home last night?
No, I-I was at the Southern
Association of Physicians'
dinner meeting at
the Americana Hotel
with a couple
hundred other doctors.
In fact, I was holding
a seat for Scott;
he said he'd be late.
He... he never showed.
Now I know why.
You two get along?
Well, we're friends.
Uh, Bob,
Lowell's worked quite a
few miracles in his career,
but even he can't be
in two places at once.
Yeah.
Well, it was dark.
The neighbor must have
mistaken him for somebody else.
Yeah.
I-I can go back to my office?
Sure. I'll even drive you.
You wear sunblock?
Do I look like I'm
going to the beach?
Dr. Carr took something
off my cheek a
couple months back.
It wasn't skin cancer,
but it could have been.
Ever since then, sunblock.
Eh, the ozone layer's
gonna make a comeback.
You watch.
That's Gary; he's my brother.
We're twins.
Lowell left a message
on my answering machine,
saying the police were
taking him for questioning,
so I got down here
as fast as I could.
Are you a doctor also?
Oh, no, ma'am, I... I
own a tune-up shop.
We doctor cars.
And did you know
the victim Dr. Weston?
Yes, of course.
Uh, did you mean to ask
Gary here that question?
Oh, you're Gary?
Very few people
can keep us straight.
Yes, uh, let's see, um,
when did you arrive at the...
at the Southern Association of
Physicians' meeting last night?
I wasn't at the
Southern Association
of Physicians' meeting.
Dr. Carr, would you
please stand up?
Thank you.
Now, Gary,
did you know the
victim Dr. Weston?
Well, no, no, not really, no.
Where were you from
7:00 to 8:00 last night?
I was in my office
at the tune-up shop
with one of my suppliers.
Thank you.
Now, Lowell...
where were you from
7:00 to 8:00 last night?
I was having drinks in the
ballroom of the Americana Hotel.
Your nurse told the police
that she overheard an argument
between you and Dr. Weston
the night before the murder...
Something concerning the
breakup of your partnership.
It was a discussion,
not an argument.
Well, it was a heated
discussion, wasn't it?
A heated discussion, yes.
Oh, you can sit down now.
I don't have any more
questions, Lieutenant.
However, I would like
to speak with Mr. Matlock
outside, please.
I have never seen
anything like this.
Oh, I know.
Lowell committed that murder.
It's perfect; he's
got an identical twin.
Nobody is gonna be
able to say for sure
who came out of that house.
You think so?
And then he tries to
frame somebody to boot,
just... oh, just making a
mockery out of the system.
I really hate that.
Julie, the man's
got an airtight alibi.
Oh, come on, Ben.
It's easy for somebody
to slip out of a party
and then slip back in unnoticed.
You're the one who's always
pointing that out in court.
And even... even
if there were people
with Lowell at that dinner,
how do we know it was
Lowell and not his brother?
W-Well, h-how do we know
the person the neighbor
saw was Lowell?
Using that logic, it
could have been Gary.
No, no, Gary didn't
have motive; Lowell did.
Julie, I just have a problem...
Ben, Ben, you and I have
spent our entire working lives
as officers of the court,
upholding the system of justice.
I'm sorry, but that man
is making fools out of us...
and I'm going to prove it.
But did Gary ever
speak to Dr. Weston?
Well, he may say hi to Scott
when he'd come to pick
me up for lunch or something,
but that was about it.
Huh, they didn't socialize?
No, never.
Why are you asking me all
these questions about Gary?
Well, if the neighbor
thought she saw you coming
out of that house, it
could have been your twin.
No, never.
My brother couldn't
commit murder.
Well, we're in the DA's hands.
We'll have to see
what she's got.
Boy, this is something.
And you did this?
Yes, I did.
You're pretty good.
Bet you're pretty
expensive, too.
Hmm, so are you.
Huh.
Maybe we could work out a trade.
You... you mean
your services for mine?
Well, physical appearances
are not inconsequential
in your line of work.
Well, I've always been quite
satisfied with my appearance.
Oh, don't take offense.
As we say in my line of work,
a little lift gives
you quite a lift.
Hmm, hmm.
Why don't you
take the book home,
look at the before
and after pictures,
and let's see if it
gives you some ideas?
Well... okay.
Hi, Benj.
Oh, Les.
- Coming or going?
- Going.
What's this?
Oh, it's a book this
plastic surgeon gave me.
I'm representing him.
Well, you know,
it might not be a
bad idea at that.
What?
Well, look at yourself.
Look at those crow's feet,
the lines on your face.
You're getting there, pal.
Couple more years.
You think so?
Oh, yeah.
Now, I, on the other hand,
will never need plastic surgery
because I'll never wrinkle.
Why?
Skin pigmentation.
See, I happen to have this
yellowish skin pigmentation
that blocks out the sun's rays.
So... I'll never wrinkle.
Huh.
You know, it's-it's true,
there are people with
a-a yellowish pigmentation.
It's natural,
but Les...
your yellowish pigmentation
could be a sign of jaundice.
What are you talking about?
Jaundice, an-and the
yellow is not just in the skin.
It's in the whites of the eyes.
Let's see.
Yep.
Have you had your
liver checked lately?
See, jaundice is a symptom.
It could be a sign of
something else wrong with you...
Anemia, poor circulation, or...
pneumonia.
It's probably nothing
to worry about, but...
why don't we look
in the phone book,
see if we can find a
specialist on liver diseases?
You'll get checked
out and then...
you will be...
Yeah, I need a set of
brake lines over here.
Yeah, this looks like a
bum alternator to me.
We're going to have to go ahead
and bleed that master
cylinder out on the clutch.
All right.
How long you been in
the tune-up business?
Close to a year now.
Doing all right?
- Oh, yeah.
- Ah.
Y-You want a soda or something?
Uh... n-no, thanks.
I understand before that, it
was the ice cream business.
Yeah.
And-and before that,
you owned a dry cleaners?
Yes, sir, I did.
And before that, it was
a Christmas tree farm.
Yeah, I've been having a
little trouble finding myself.
Yeah, unlike your brother,
who made it right away.
You jealous?
No, no, I-I'm-I'm not the...
I'm not the jealous type, no.
W-We get along well.
Oh.
I understand, uh,
you tried to borrow
some money from him
a few months back,
and he turned you down.
Yeah.
How did he turn you down?
Well, he gave me that speech
on the value of the dollar
and how adversity
builds character,
and he was right, of course.
Yes.
So where'd you
finally get the money?
Scott Weston?
Well, no, I...
I mean, I-I hardly
knew Dr. Weston.
You, uh, s-see
that hat over there?
It was left here by
a supplier of mine,
a gentleman named Duke McKenna.
We had a meeting the night
that Dr. Weston was killed.
I-If you don't believe me,
you can call him
up, you can ask him.
Hmm.
Well, maybe I will.
Yeah.
So, you ever need
a tune-up... I'll call.
♪♪
Pretty good myself.
How you doing, my friend?
You look great.
You came through for me, Gary.
I'm grateful and impressed.
Well, thanks.
Does that mean we're square?
You bet.
Any time, my friend.
Any time.
Della, is my brother here yet?
Here. I'm here.
Come on, let's grab a sandwich.
Is this your pen?
No.
I think you meant
to ask Dr. Carr.
Is this your pen?
Well, it... it could be.
It's a company I
do business with.
The sales rep often leaves
promotional items like this
behind after he's made a call.
Well, this pen was found on
the ground outside the window
of Doreen Ferguson's home.
The district attorney's
concluded that it fell out
of the killer's pocket
when he entered the house
through the window.
I'm afraid you're under arrest.
What?!
You're gonna arrest him
because of some lousy little pen?
- Gary, it's-it's okay.
- That's nuts!
I mean, there must be
hundreds of pens like that.
What, are you gonna go out
and arrest all those people, too?
I'll take good care of him.
Hi, Ben!
- Hi, Les.
- Coffee?
- No, thanks.
You son of a gun, you
really had me going yesterday
with that jaundice.
I went to my doctor, and
I got a clean bill of health.
Oh, I'm glad, Les.
Jaundice, you son of a gun.
He did say I was a
little anemic, though.
So he gave me
some iron pills to take.
And I said, "I don't want
to take too much iron, Doc.
I don't want to
clank when I walk!"
He laughed.
It's funny, yeah.
Yeah, what's in the sack here?
Oh, well, I-I don't understand
why anyone would want to go
through the pain and expense
of plastic surgery when
there's a simple solution.
Look, guys wear
toupees, women wear wigs,
false eyelashes and whatnot.
Okay, you're going
out for the evening.
What's wrong with this?
- Turn around.
- Hmm?
Well, go ahead,
turn around, will you?
All right.
Okay.
Is this real or what?
I mean, you can wear it all
evening. Who would know?
Well...
There's-there's one
problem I see right off.
Your mouth doesn't
move when you talk.
So what?
Gregory Peck's mouth
doesn't move when he talks,
and he gets away with it.
Hi.
- Well, hi.
- Conrad.
Les, how are you doing?
Oh, can't complain,
can't complain.
Well, I'd better go.
- Oh, don't rush off.
- Stick around.
No, I got an appointment
to have my shoes half-soled.
So, time is of the essence.
- He was wearing a mask.
- I know.
Have you ever thought
he was a little weird?
Oh, yes, often.
Yeah, yeah.
- So, how'd it go?
- Oh, good, good.
This morning I tailed
Gary from his tune-up shop
to a bar on La Grande,
where he had a very brief
but lively conversation
with this guy.
Name's William Hodges.
Been in town less than a month.
Started managing the bar
where he met with
Gary about a week ago.
Know what they
were talking about?
Couldn't hear.
Is there some connection
between him and Dr. Weston?
Not that I know of.
I did find out
something interesting
about the bar though.
Used to be owned by Ken Groman.
Oh, yeah, mobster.
He disappeared about a year ago
after being indicted
for racketeering.
Who owns it now?
Holding company, the
Guilfoyle Corporation.
Now keep digging. Maybe... Yeah?
Yeah, I was just on
my way down there.
Run that by me again?
Ben, I'm-I'm telling you, I was
given that pen after the murder.
- Are you sure?
- Yes.
Ask Lori, my nurse, or call
the sales rep and ask him.
I'm absolutely positive
that he came to see me
- the day after the murder.
- After?
- Yeah.
- After.
Someone must've stolen that pen
and put it under that window
deliberately to frame you.
- Really?
- Yeah.
Hey!
Oh, hey, I'm sor... sorry, I
got something in my contact.
Let me buy you another.
No, don't worry about it.
Don't move! Please don't move.
My contact fell out.
You might step on it... here,
drinks all around, everybody.
Just everybody, just
please stay in your seats.
This should only take a minute.
Hot dog. Yeah.
"Seek and ye shall find."
I'm sorry about that.
He stopped by the day
after Dr. Weston died.
I know because he
gave me a pen, too.
I don't suppose either one
of you remember his name.
Um, yes, Brian something.
- Terwilliger.
- Yes.
Hits on me every
time he comes in.
- Oh.
- Well...
the pen's not here.
Thanks for your help, Lori.
Yeah.
So, now what happens?
We go to trial.
But we've just established
that I couldn't have
dropped the pen
on the night of the murder
because I didn't have it yet.
Doesn't that blow a
hole in the DA's case?
Lori heard you arguing
with the deceased
shortly before the murder.
And another witness said she
saw you coming out of the house.
She's got a case.
I see.
Lowell, how you doing?
Oh, hi. Fine.
Um, Dr. Alvin Prescott, this
is my attorney, Ben Matlock.
- Hello.
- I'm honored.
Listen, I was just
in the neighborhood.
I thought I'd stop by
and pick up the file.
What file?
The one that you promised
me at the Association dinner.
Your notes on your new
skin grafting procedure.
You said I could have them.
Right. Right.
Um, I'll run you off a copy.
Why don't you stay right here?
- Okay, I'll see you tomorrow.
- Yeah, right.
Hmm.
Truly, it has been an
honor meeting you.
I'd like to think that
you are to criminal law,
what I am to plastic surgery.
At approximately 7:15, I saw
a man leave Doreen's house
through the front door.
Is the man you saw
in the courtroom today?
Oh, yes, he's right over there.
Thank you.
Mr. Matlock.
Um, Miss Stanford,
uh, are you sure
this is the man
you saw that night?
Positive.
The porch light was on.
I saw his face clearly.
You're sure you saw this
man and not this man?
Once again, Miss Stanford,
whom did you see that night?
I... don't know.
Thank you.
Redirect?
Yes, Your Honor.
Miss Stanford, what
did the man you saw
do after he left your
neighbor's house?
He got into a car
and drove away.
And what did that car look like?
Uh, it was maroon, one of those
new Japanese luxury sports cars.
Is this the car he got into?
Yes, that's the car.
Let the record show the
witness positively identified
a photo of the car
owned by the defendant,
Dr. Lowell Carr.
That's all, Your Honor.
So noted.
Ben?
In here.
- Hey.
- You got something?
Do I ever.
When I started checking
into the background
of that guy that Gary Carr met
with, I came up with nothing.
Zero.
He's got no Social Security
card, no driver's license.
- That's odd.
- That's what I thought.
So, I stole a glass that
he'd been drinking out of,
and I had them check the prints.
What are you doing?
Nothing.
I-I just thought I saw
something on my face
that wasn't there yesterday.
It's probably just
a little something
that comes with age, huh?
Yeah.
So, guess whose
prints were on the glass.
- Whose?
- Ken Groman's.
That's impossible.
He disappeared a year ago.
I know what Ken
Groman looks like.
Everybody knows what
Ken Groman looks like.
His picture was in
the paper for weeks.
- Plastic surgery?
- Right.
- Lowell.
- Yep.
Oh, no.
What?
Dr. Prescott.
Who's that?
Someone who was
with Lowell at that dinner.
He asked him to send him
something out of his files,
only he never did.
He didn't?
No.
'Cause Lowell
wasn't at that dinner.
Julie was right.
He was at Doreen
Ferguson's, killing his partner.
Hey. Sleep much?
No. I couldn't get
my mind off the...
Dr. Weston must have found out
that Lowell redid
Ken Groman's face,
and that's why he wanted
to dissolve the partnership.
So, what are you gonna do?
Well, I was hired
to give Lowell Carr the
best defense possible,
so I guess I'll give
it a shot. Hmm.
Mr. Matlock, you may
call your first witness.
Your Honor, I call
Mr. Gary Carr to the stand.
What's going on?
You'll see. You'll see.
Well, what's it like
to be an identical
twin, Mr. Carr?
Uh, well, I've just always
thought it was a fact of life.
Yeah, you don't
mind being a twin?
No.
I should think
it'd be difficult.
People always
trying to tell you apart.
He's the smart one.
He's the athletic one.
He's the successful one.
Doesn't it bother you?
Well, sometimes, yeah.
By the way, uh, which
one is the smarter?
Well, I-I don't
know about smarter.
Lowell usually got
better grades than I did.
You the athletic one?
Well, we were
both fairly athletic.
He tended to play for string
- more often than I did.
- You were the successful one?
Well, no, not-not yet.
I-I haven't really found
myself career-wise.
Actually, you filed
for bankruptcy twice
in the past seven
years, haven't you?
Yeah.
Has your brother ever
filed for bankruptcy?
No, never.
He's smarter than you,
better at sports,
more successful.
You resent the hell out
of your brother, don't you?
Objection. Whatever
ill feelings this witness may
or may not have
toward his brother
are not germane to this case.
Uh, Your Honor, this
case rests on the fact
that someone who looked
like my client was seen
leaving the scene of the crime.
Now, this witness's emotional
state is inarguably germane.
Objection overruled.
Please answer the question.
Well, I'd be lying if I... said
I didn't sometimes
resent him a little.
You-you asked your brother
to loan you $20,000
a few months ago,
and he turned you down.
That make you mad?
For a while...
It made you furious, didn't it?
He humiliated you one more time,
but this time, you were
gonna make him pay
by framing him for a murder
that you committed, right?
I didn't kill anybody.
Act-actually, you
concocted two frames.
You lured Dr. Weston to
Miss Ferguson's house,
having heard that she
was upset with him,
and killed him with
one of her knives.
And then instead of leaving
by a window or something,
you went out the front door,
knowing damn well
the porch light was on.
You knew somebody would see you.
You wanted to be seen.
You wanted somebody
to positively identify
your brother's car.
You wanted that pen to be found.
You wanted the
police to conclude that
your brother had
killed his partner.
That's not true.
You had keys to his house
and his car, didn't you?
Well, yeah...
Knowing that he was at
that-that Association dinner,
you went to the hotel
where it was being held,
drove his car
from the parking lot
over to Miss Ferguson's house,
committed the murder
and drove back, didn't you?
No. I-I didn't.
I-I was at my shop all night.
No, you weren't.
I called Mr. McKenna.
He left at 7:00,
but then after he
left, he realized
he's left his hat
in your office,
so he drove back, got
back at 7:30, but he couldn't
get his hat because you
weren't there, were you?
I just went across the
street to get a sandwich.
Light was out, the
door was closed,
your car was gone.
You weren't there.
You were at Miss Ferguson's,
framing your
brother, weren't you?
I wasn't there.
I was at the Association dinner.
Oh, come on. Come on!
To get into that dinner,
you'd have to
show a positive I.D.,
wear a name tag,
go by security guards.
You weren't there. Lowell was.
That wasn't Lowell. It was me.
You'd say anything to
save your skin, wouldn't you?
I can prove it. I...
I-I can tell you who I
talked to, what I said,
wh-where I sat, what
was on the menu.
I-I can tell you everything.
Ar-Are you asking this court
to believe that your brother
planted a piece of evidence
at the scene of the crime
to incriminate himself?
I put the pen there.
Gary, shut up.
I did it...
I did it because
Lowell told me to.
He-he knew he'd be able to
show that it had been planted
so people would think
that he'd been framed.
I... I can't believe
what I'm hearing.
Murdering Scott
Weston was his idea.
It wasn't mine. It was his.
It was his!
Gary, stop it!
Sorry. I...
I don't want to take
the rap for this alone.
Uh... Uh...
You Honor, uh...
could I ask for
a... a brief recess
so that I could confer
with my client in private?
Yes.
What the hell are
you doing, Ben?
Trying to defend you.
Defend me?! You're burying me!
I was trying to show
reasonable doubt
by making it look
like Gary had done it.
How was I to know that
you were in on it together?
You did it, didn't you?
Your partner found out
that you operated on Ken Groman.
You changed his appearance
to keep him from
going to prison.
The $20,000 that Gary wanted
from me, he got from Groman.
Couldn't pay it back?
If I didn't operate,
he'd kill him.
Mm.
Did you make Gary
help you murder your partner?
No.
He wanted to.
He said he got
me into this mess,
so he should help me out of it.
So what happens?
He helps me.
And screws up again.
Your Honor, my client
wishes to change his plea
from not guilty to guilty.
That seems entirely
appropriate, Mr. Matlock.
I'm revoking bail.
I'm instructing the bailiff
to remand the defendant's
brother, Gary Carr,
to the lockup,
and urge the prosecutor
to file charges immediately.
Court is adjourned.
Well, you sure
called that one right.
What's more important...
I won the case.
- Yeah.
- More or less.
Yeah, and I lost my
shot at a free facelift.
Are you thinking
about having a facelift?
Well, it's like
Lowell Carr said:
"A little lift gives
you quite a lift."
Ah. I kind of like you
just the way you are.
Yeah, but you're saying
that 'cause you won.
www.tvsubtitles.net